<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>math club on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/math-club/</link>
    <description>Recent content in math club on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/math-club/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>Addressing a need for guidance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics of Billiards</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/billiards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/billiards/</guid>
      <description>Billiards night was one of the first events that Christina and I plan for Math Club. It was a relatively simple event, focused on bringing together people For a night of pool and pizza. We played videos about billiards, including ones that went over the geometry of planning different types of shots on televisions in the background of the pool hall. We held this event several times over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</guid>
      <description>In my first year (2014-2015) of becoming involved in Math Club, I threw this poster together for a pretty simple event.   For Pi Day, Math Club organized several events over the years that focused on simply enjoying the festivities, eating pie, and trying to bring in people from outside of the department&amp;rsquo;s and engage with the broader community.
  Second year.   One year we chose to fundraise and partnered with a local pizzeria to set up a day where a portion of their profits would be donated to girls who code, a nonprofit that focuses on education in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>