<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>math club on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/math-club/</link>
    <description>Recent content in math club on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/math-club/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics of Billiards</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/billiards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/billiards/</guid>
      <description>Billiards night was one of the first events that Christina and I plan for Math Club. It was a relatively simple event, focused on bringing together people For a night of pool and pizza. We played videos about billiards, including ones that went over the geometry of planning different types of shots on televisions in the background of the pool hall. We held this event several times over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>