<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fundraising on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/fundraising/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fundraising on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/fundraising/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Math || Art?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIAM</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</guid>
      <description>The following is an edited version of an end-of-year summary report sent to the SIAM.
SIAM and Math Club have established three core pillars upon which to form themselves within the Department of Mathematical and Statistical Sciences at CU Denver:
 service, scholarship, and community engagement.  In addressing service, we have regularly facilitated participation in regional science fairs, organized a semesterly food bank drive to benefit homeless students on campus (Note: our department was the most successful donor on campus last semester), and have begun to integrate charitable fundraising into our community events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students Today, Alumni Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/stat/</guid>
      <description>Co-President focusing on growing a new organization in the Office of Advancement, with a particular emphasis on developing a social media strategy.
I began my co-presidency of Students Today, Alumni Tomorrow officially in the spring semester of 2019, though technically I was serving as interim President for fall 2018 as well.
The focus of the organization is to better connect students and alumni, educating students about the ways in which University Advancement operates and why it is so important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/foodbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/foodbank/</guid>
      <description>As part of the activities we implemented in Math Club, we got the Math Department involved in a campus-wide competition to donate food to the campus food pantry, which serves students in crisis1.
We routinely placed in the top three, and even took first place twice, beating out the Office of the Dean and the Graduate School.
  We had three purple bins in the department, and we made sure they all looked like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary During the last semester of my first year in graduate school (spring 2015), I volunteered for the Study Hall that was being put on by the department. I was inspired by that event to get in touch with the professor who organized it, and asked about interest in a Math Club. I was told that it had languished over the years but I was welcome to revive it (he was willing to be the faculty advisor), and he put me in touch with an undergraduate student that he thought would be good to partner up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</guid>
      <description>In my first year (2014-2015) of becoming involved in Math Club, I threw this poster together for a pretty simple event.   For Pi Day, Math Club organized several events over the years that focused on simply enjoying the festivities, eating pie, and trying to bring in people from outside of the department&amp;rsquo;s and engage with the broader community.
  Second year.   One year we chose to fundraise and partnered with a local pizzeria to set up a day where a portion of their profits would be donated to girls who code, a nonprofit that focuses on education in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary Along with some good friends, I helped re-establish this defunct club and secure funding for club meetings and events.
My primary responsibilities included all publicity operations and planning the charity fundraisers.
We held weekly meetings and grew from two tables to as many as twelve simultaneous games happening. Snacks were provided and occasionally we were able to provide pizza.
  Waiting for announcements to end so chess can start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>