<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>poker on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/poker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in poker on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/poker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Game of Poker</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/poker/</guid>
      <description>This was a really fun project I undertook for a Math Club game night in 2016 with my friend Elliott Regan, who helped me program this in Javascript and embed into an earlier version of my website.
Premise Dr. Burt Simon and I had previously collaborated on a paper.
Rules The rules are listed in short form below the game demonstration below. Gambling would occur on pre-determined intervals (timer), or whenever someone wants to (if you enjoy a bit of chaos).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poker &amp; Game Night</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/gamenight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/gamenight/</guid>
      <description>Math Club held several Poker and Game nights, where we provided food and snacks for students to come and relax after a long day at school and enjoy a social space that did not involve alcohol/drugs (nor much math).
At one of these, we also had the opportunity to introduce a game that Dr. Simon I had worked on, since I finally managed to write a program in a way that could be used by other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Cards</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/blackjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/blackjack/</guid>
      <description>As part of a course I took, I was tasked to perform a semester-long research project on a topic of my choosing. I had a nascent interest in blackjack after seeing the film 21, and wanted to learn more about the history and mathematics behind how/why card counting worked for the MIT blackjack team so well.
This research project was my first introduction of Monte-Carlo methods, probability and expectation, and game theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>