<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>events on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in events on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FRAMSC</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</guid>
      <description>This student conference brings together students from a number of universities in the Rocky Mountain Region to give presentations in an intimate environment. I have been involved in some way or another in its organization for all my years at CU Denver.
As President I helped change the way we secure funding for the event and increased our budget for food by working out an agreement with our student government association to co-sponsor the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>