<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>outreach on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/outreach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in outreach on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Math || Art?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitterbots</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/twitterbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/twitterbots/</guid>
      <description>I decided to explore the use of Twitter&amp;rsquo;s API in Python to perform some fun projects.
I wrote a Twitter bot called &amp;ldquo;Random Art Baby&amp;rdquo; that when prompted, would respond to users with artwork.
This art was randomly generated using the library I had developed for my initial exploration with graphical user interfaces for visualizing probability distributions.
This also provided me the opportunity to explore some machine learning code for the generation of natural language speech based on training examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/talk/racas18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/talk/racas18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</guid>
      <description>In my first year (2014-2015) of becoming involved in Math Club, I threw this poster together for a pretty simple event.   For Pi Day, Math Club organized several events over the years that focused on simply enjoying the festivities, eating pie, and trying to bring in people from outside of the department&amp;rsquo;s and engage with the broader community.
  Second year.   One year we chose to fundraise and partnered with a local pizzeria to set up a day where a portion of their profits would be donated to girls who code, a nonprofit that focuses on education in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</guid>
      <description>After my first experience with writing software in the summer of 2013, I wanted to learn how to write software that was usable by other people1.
I thought that learning how graphical user interfaces work would be a good place to start. Since I already knew Matlab, I chose that for my programming language.
I performed the project under the direction of use of Dr. Yusuf Bilgic, who generally gave me free rein to pursue the project in any direction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>