<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>events on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in events on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Math || Art?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Nights</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/movienight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/movienight/</guid>
      <description>Math Club began to host regular movie nights each semester, highlighting films about mathematicians. We hoped to reach a broader audience outside the math department by hosting these events in very public locations with generous catering budgets.
Films Watched:
 The Imitation Game The Man Who Knew Infinity Hidden Figures  Download Game Night Funding Presentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poker &amp; Game Night</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/gamenight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/gamenight/</guid>
      <description>Math Club held several Poker and Game nights, where we provided food and snacks for students to come and relax after a long day at school and enjoy some social spaces that did not involve alcohol or drugs (or math). At one of these, we also had the opportunity to introduce a game that Dr. Simon I had worked on, since I finally managed to write a program in a way that could be used by other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary Along with some good friends, I helped re-establish this defunct club and secure funding for club meetings and events.
My primary responsibilities included all publicity operations and planning the charity fundraisers.
We held weekly meetings and grew from two tables to as many as twelve simultaneous games happening. Snacks were provided and occasionally we were able to provide pizza.
  Waiting for announcements to end so chess can start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>