<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>outreach on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/outreach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in outreach on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Math || Art?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIAM</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</guid>
      <description>The following is an edited version of an end-of-year summary report sent to the SIAM.
SIAM and Math Club have established three core pillars upon which to form themselves within the Department of Mathematical and Statistical Sciences at CU Denver:
 service, scholarship, and community engagement.  In addressing service, we have regularly facilitated participation in regional science fairs, organized a semesterly food bank drive to benefit homeless students on campus (Note: our department was the most successful donor on campus last semester), and have begun to integrate charitable fundraising into our community events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students Today, Alumni Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/stat/</guid>
      <description>Co-President focusing on growing a new organization in the Office of Advancement, with a particular emphasis on developing a social media strategy.
I began my co-presidency of Students Today, Alumni Tomorrow officially in the spring semester of 2019, though technically I was serving as interim President for fall 2018 as well.
The focus of the organization is to better connect students and alumni, educating students about the ways in which University Advancement operates and why it is so important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/talk/racas18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/talk/racas18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary During the last semester of my first year in graduate school (spring 2015), I volunteered for the Study Hall that was being put on by the department. I was inspired by that event to get in touch with the professor who organized it, and asked about interest in a Math Club. I was told that it had languished over the years but I was welcome to revive it (he was willing to be the faculty advisor), and he put me in touch with an undergraduate student that he thought would be good to partner up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FRAMSC</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</guid>
      <description>This student conference brings together students from a number of universities in the Rocky Mountain Region to give presentations in an intimate environment. I have been involved in some way or another in its organization for all my years at CU Denver.
As President I helped change the way we secure funding for the event and increased our budget for food by working out an agreement with our student government association to co-sponsor the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</guid>
      <description>The department’s semesterly two-day study hall that precedes final examinations experienced a dramatic increase in attendance.
I attribute this to my aggressive advertising efforts and the President (Christina Ebben, pictured below) and I coordinating an unprecedented funding campaign to attract attendees.
Snacks (fruits, nuts, chips, sodas, etc) and coffee were plentiful fuel for students, and lunches were purchased for the volunteers. The tutors provided by Math Club and SIAM provide much needed emotional and educational support for the student body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary Along with some good friends, I helped re-establish this defunct club and secure funding for club meetings and events.
My primary responsibilities included all publicity operations and planning the charity fundraisers.
We held weekly meetings and grew from two tables to as many as twelve simultaneous games happening. Snacks were provided and occasionally we were able to provide pizza.
  Waiting for announcements to end so chess can start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAC</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mac/</guid>
      <description>Four years of active participation in a Service Organization. Almost countless events.
I joined my first semester in undergrad, and remained an active member every semester that I was enrolled in college.
Pillars of the Organization  Scholarship Service Unity Fitness Loyalty   Here is a reproduction of a Lamron Article about the organization. It was written the semester I joined! 
 Men of Action and Change, an organization founded at Geneseo in 1997, is a multicultural group dedicated to continuing a legacy of service and support to the local and global communities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>