<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jupyter on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/jupyter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jupyter on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/jupyter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Science</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/openscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/openscience/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyterhub Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/devlog/jupyterhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/devlog/jupyterhub/</guid>
      <description>Jan 1, 2019 Status Report Okay so where are we at?
 Spawner needs to be sussed out. Right now I really like DockerSpawner, and it seems to persist storage.  Each student gets a user account but it&amp;rsquo;s only used for authenetication right now. Can&amp;rsquo;t figure out volume-mapping.  With dockerspawner.DockerSpawner:
 Each time someone is logged in, a container is either loaded up or built from jupyterlab_img container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Exploration with Docker &amp; Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/devlog/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/devlog/docker/</guid>
      <description>Dec 22, 2018 Today I began to structure and fill in the basic information for the Open Science/Docker Documentation.
12/24/2019 - 01/01/2019
Today I started by watching a video to be aware of the problems I might face going forward with JupyterHub. I watched someone from Berkeley describe how they&amp;rsquo;ve scaled to thousands of users across many professors and managed to not grow their IT team while doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter for All the Things</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/slides/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/slides/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>Scientific Computation for Research and Teaching with Jupyter Michael Pilosov, University of Colorado Denver
Motivation and Qualifiers  Love applied math&amp;hellip; Hate the learning curve Want to make (computational) math accessible Some familiarity with website design Vague understanding of application architecture  Backstory  Wanted to embed interactive content into website Difficulty with back-end, lack of understanding Kept seeing some of the same words/phrases  Docker, Servers, Databases, Ports, Containers, Volumes, Mounting, Images, Spawning, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>