<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SIAM</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</guid>
      <description>The following is an edited version of an end-of-year summary report sent to the SIAM.
SIAM and Math Club have established three core pillars upon which to form themselves within the Department of Mathematical and Statistical Sciences at CU Denver:
 service, scholarship, and community engagement.  In addressing service, we have regularly facilitated participation in regional science fairs, organized a semesterly food bank drive to benefit homeless students on campus (Note: our department was the most successful donor on campus last semester), and have begun to integrate charitable fundraising into our community events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Game of Poker</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/poker/</guid>
      <description>This was a really fun project I undertook for a Math Club game night in 2016 with my friend Elliott Regan, who helped me program this in Javascript and embed into an earlier version of my website.
Premise Dr. Burt Simon and I had previously collaborated on a paper.
Rules The rules are listed in short form below the game demonstration below. Gambling would occur on pre-determined intervals (timer), or whenever someone wants to (if you enjoy a bit of chaos).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/masters/</guid>
      <description>Summary My advisor developed a framework for solving a large class of problems of particular interest to the engineering disciplines. Starting as a graduate research assistant under his direction in the summer of 2015, I began to learn about this new method and explore implications of how measurements of physical systems are taken on our ability to accurately describe parameter uncertainty sets.
You can read more about it below, but overall, my focus on skewness ended up playing a less important role when we developed a sample-based approach to solving the same problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Nights</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/movienight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/movienight/</guid>
      <description>Math Club began to host regular movie nights each semester, highlighting films about mathematicians. We hoped to reach a broader audience outside the math department by hosting these events in very public locations with generous catering budgets.
Films Watched:
 The Imitation Game The Man Who Knew Infinity Hidden Figures  Download Game Night Funding Presentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poker &amp; Game Night</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/gamenight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/gamenight/</guid>
      <description>Math Club held several Poker and Game nights, where we provided food and snacks for students to come and relax after a long day at school and enjoy a social space that did not involve alcohol/drugs (nor much math).
At one of these, we also had the opportunity to introduce a game that Dr. Simon I had worked on, since I finally managed to write a program in a way that could be used by other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics of Billiards</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/billiards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/billiards/</guid>
      <description>Billiards night was one of the first events that Christina and I plan for Math Club. It was a relatively simple event, focused on bringing together people For a night of pool and pizza. We played videos about billiards, including ones that went over the geometry of planning different types of shots on televisions in the background of the pool hall. We held this event several times over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/foodbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/foodbank/</guid>
      <description>As part of the activities we implemented in Math Club, we got the Math Department involved in a campus-wide competition to donate food to the campus food pantry, which serves students in crisis1.
We routinely placed in the top three, and even took first place twice, beating out the Office of the Dean and the Graduate School.
  We had three purple bins in the department, and we made sure they all looked like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary During the last semester of my first year in graduate school (spring 2015), I volunteered for the Study Hall that was being put on by the department. I was inspired by that event to get in touch with the professor who organized it, and asked about interest in a Math Club. I was told that it had languished over the years but I was welcome to revive it (he was willing to be the faculty advisor), and he put me in touch with an undergraduate student that he thought would be good to partner up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Wildlife</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Given that we do not know exactly where animals will go, how do we set up a network of sensors to track them?
I managed a group of four undergraduates through a semester-long research project concerning the placement of sensors in an environment where the travel patterns of animals is unknown. My responsibilities included:
 defining the scope of research and breaking goals down into explicit deliverables, overseeing timeline of research progress, keeping students on deadline, developing outlines of software and clearly defined what their contributions would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FRAMSC</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/framsc/</guid>
      <description>This student conference brings together students from a number of universities in the Rocky Mountain Region to give presentations in an intimate environment. I have been involved in some way or another in its organization for all my years at CU Denver.
As President I helped change the way we secure funding for the event and increased our budget for food by working out an agreement with our student government association to co-sponsor the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/studyhall/</guid>
      <description>The department’s semesterly two-day study hall that precedes final examinations experienced a dramatic increase in attendance.
I attribute this to my aggressive advertising efforts and the President (Christina Ebben, pictured below) and I coordinating an unprecedented funding campaign to attract attendees.
Snacks (fruits, nuts, chips, sodas, etc) and coffee were plentiful fuel for students, and lunches were purchased for the volunteers. The tutors provided by Math Club and SIAM provide much needed emotional and educational support for the student body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/piday/</guid>
      <description>In my first year (2014-2015) of becoming involved in Math Club, I threw this poster together for a pretty simple event.   For Pi Day, Math Club organized several events over the years that focused on simply enjoying the festivities, eating pie, and trying to bring in people from outside of the department&amp;rsquo;s and engage with the broader community.
  Second year.   One year we chose to fundraise and partnered with a local pizzeria to set up a day where a portion of their profits would be donated to girls who code, a nonprofit that focuses on education in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>