<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mathematical Michael</title>
    <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mathematical Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Start of the Semester</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/start/</guid>
      <description>Welcome new students!  -- It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see everyone back on campus again.
Come say hi!
 (Student Commons 4th floor)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mathematics of Hallucination</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/hallucinating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/hallucinating/</guid>
      <description>I found this article incredibly fascinating. I just had to post it here for posterity.
From Quanta Magazine:
 There is still much more to understand about hallucinations. Jean-Paul Sartre experimented with mescaline in Paris in 1935 and found it distorted his visual perception for weeks. Houses appeared to have “leering faces, all eyes and jaws,” clock faces looked like owls, and he saw crabs following him around all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/machinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/machinelearning/</guid>
      <description>Article: Learn Math for Machine Learning This article was one I found insightful and I agreed with most of its advice. Give it a read.
 To frame the math prerequisites, I first propose different mindsets and strategies for approaching your math education outside of traditional classroom settings.
 The links at the bottom of the article (partially reproduced below), led me to some thought-provoking reading:
 How to Read Mathematics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download your Linkedin Contacts</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/linkedin-contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/linkedin-contacts/</guid>
      <description>This is a really useful feature if you want to mine your network for possible leads and resources.
 Go to https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/member-data
 Download Your Data &amp;gt; Pick and Choose &amp;gt; Connections
 Request Archive (enter password), and wait until your download is ready.
 You will receive an email with a link to download your archive. Enjoy your data!
  Source: Alignable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Rocky Opportunity</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/rocky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/rocky/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote up a blog post on SIAM News about the importance of Uncertainty Quantification, particularly in the context of storm surge threats to coastal communities.
Check it out! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Skills Gap</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/skillsgap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/skillsgap/</guid>
      <description>I live and breathe applied mathematics. Challenge problems are what I thrive on.
As such, programming comprises the vast majority of the &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; that I do. Theories are nothing without evidence, and my laboratory is the computer. I am a computational scientist, being trained as a mathematician.
Programming has enabled me to do so much more than the research I perform as part of my dissertation work. One can argue that my most marketable skill after graduation will be my software development experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What The Function?</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/function/</guid>
      <description>To supplement my graduate student income, I have been tutoring in my department for several years. Many know how to manipulate them, but have never actually considered&amp;hellip; What is a function?  Metaphor allows us to explain that which is novel with that which is familiar.
 Imagine you have a blender. If you put in ingredients for a smoothie, you better get a smoothie out. If pancake batter magically appeared instead, you&amp;rsquo;d either be elated (because, pancakes), or really really upset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Process</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/process/</guid>
      <description> The Process  You’re not lost in life, you’re just early in the process
  Gary Vaynerchuck  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Honda</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/honda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/honda/</guid>
      <description>The Individual and the Group There has always been something about group-work in school that I resisted during childhood. I resented the forced pace of it all.
I now have the vantage point of a teacher, and understand the difficulty of running a classroom that caters to a wide range of student capabilities and backgrounds. Group-work is a way that I now attempt to stimulate collaboration and force those who &amp;ldquo;get it&amp;rdquo; to examine their understanding by explaining it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Deadlines Aren&#39;t Really Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/deadlines/</guid>
      <description>I have always been the kind of person who takes deadlines seriously. I like to set deadlines for myself well ahead of the real ones just in case I want to make last minute revisions.
Despite years of applying for/to all sorts of academia-related things, I still often end up working on final tweaks at the last minute. Who knows if these are beneficial or not?
In one sense, I&amp;rsquo;m a big believer in deadlines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Good Advising: Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising3/</guid>
      <description>You have to find someone you want to learn from.
That is what can make the difference between five years in graduate school and seven years. It can mean the difference between being lost and being directed in a productive manner.
Maybe I got lucky, but my present advisor has rarely let me go in a research direction that didn&amp;rsquo;t bear fruit of some kind or another. He knew when to shield me from complexity and when to implore me to pursue deeper understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Good Advising: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising2/</guid>
      <description>Getting to Grad School As an undergraduate, I first experienced the extent to which mathematics could be broadly applied to &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; problems, and recognized the potential to make substantive change. I set my sights on a job in industry, with vague hopes and aspirations as to what such a thing might look like. I had been applying to summer programs that would potentially expose me to application areas every.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Good Advising: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising1/</guid>
      <description>Opportunistic Disparity and Serendipity This past summer I worked at a national laboratory that sees several thousand students come through its doors each year to develop their skills and networks. Orientation blew my mind. When my group was surveyed regarding where we were academically, I realized that graduate students made up something like a tenth of the room.
 Wait&amp;hellip; how did these kids get jobs here so early on?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>