<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Science</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/openscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/openscience/</guid>
      <description>Improved student access to technology by deploying JupyterHub on powerful servers in my Math Department, learning a ton of dev-ops along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitterbots</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/twitterbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/twitterbots/</guid>
      <description>I decided to explore the use of Twitter&amp;rsquo;s API in Python to perform some fun projects.
I wrote a Twitter bot called &amp;ldquo;Random Art Baby&amp;rdquo; that when prompted, would respond to users with artwork.
This art was randomly generated using the library I had developed for my initial exploration with graphical user interfaces for visualizing probability distributions.
This also provided me the opportunity to explore some machine learning code for the generation of natural language speech based on training examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharma Mutuals</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/pharma/</guid>
      <description>This was a self-directed research project that had its origins in my desire to better understand the contents of an enticing TED talk that I watched during the first week of my last semester as an undergraduate student.
  What grabbed my attention was that the speaker (Stein) invited scrutiny of their source code, making it [publicly available on GitHub][code]. This event likely seeded my interest in open-source philosophies and diving into this project was an early attempt to learn more about how other people write code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>