<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2014 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/2014/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2014 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</guid>
      <description>I began graduate school in the summer of 2014 as a summer graduate research assistant. I approached Dr. Burt Simon to learn about his research as I was casually walking around the department while working on the LAPACK project. His research was concerned with modeling population dynamics to study the conditions under which cooperation could evolve from a mutation to the norm within a system that is inherently competitive.
I was really interested in the problem he was working on and asked if I could see his software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAPACK</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/lapack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/lapack/</guid>
      <description>My Brief Experience I was fortunate enough to be funded by Dr. Julien Langou during my summer proceeding entering graduate school. This relief from teaching was especially helpful for my transition into post-graduate education, and I was given the opportunity to explore a number of topics that I knew nothing about.
For the first time, I found myself working on an object-oriented task in a programming language that was strongly typed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharma Mutuals</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/pharma/</guid>
      <description>This was a self-directed research project that had its origins in my desire to better understand the contents of an enticing TED talk that I watched during the first week of my last semester as an undergraduate student.
  What grabbed my attention was that the speaker (Stein) invited scrutiny of their source code, making it [publicly available on GitHub][code]. This event likely seeded my interest in open-source philosophies and diving into this project was an early attempt to learn more about how other people write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</guid>
      <description>After my first experience with writing software in the summer of 2013, I wanted to learn how to write software that was usable by other people1.
I thought that learning how graphical user interfaces work would be a good place to start. Since I already knew Matlab, I chose that for my programming language.
I performed the project under the direction of use of Dr. Yusuf Bilgic, who generally gave me free rein to pursue the project in any direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary Along with some good friends, I helped re-establish this defunct club and secure funding for club meetings and events.
My primary responsibilities included all publicity operations and planning the charity fundraisers.
We held weekly meetings and grew from two tables to as many as twelve simultaneous games happening. Snacks were provided and occasionally we were able to provide pizza.
  Waiting for announcements to end so chess can start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>