<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fall 2018 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/fall-2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fall 2018 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/fall-2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/thesis/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIAM</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/siam/</guid>
      <description>The following is an edited version of an end-of-year summary report sent to the SIAM.
SIAM and Math Club have established three core pillars upon which to form themselves within the Department of Mathematical and Statistical Sciences at CU Denver:
 service, scholarship, and community engagement.  In addressing service, we have regularly facilitated participation in regional science fairs, organized a semesterly food bank drive to benefit homeless students on campus (Note: our department was the most successful donor on campus last semester), and have begun to integrate charitable fundraising into our community events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students Today, Alumni Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/stat/</guid>
      <description>Co-President focusing on growing a new organization in the Office of Advancement, with a particular emphasis on developing a social media strategy.
I began my co-presidency of Students Today, Alumni Tomorrow officially in the spring semester of 2019, though technically I was serving as interim President for fall 2018 as well.
The focus of the organization is to better connect students and alumni, educating students about the ways in which University Advancement operates and why it is so important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DCI</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/dci/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/dci/</guid>
      <description>The novel framework for solving inverse problems in which all of my doctoral work has been grounded.
In the broadest terms possible, Data-Consistent Inversion (DCI) is a new approach to answer questions about the conditions under which observations can occur.
What makes it particularly special is that in a sense, this approach leverages the &amp;ldquo;best of both worlds&amp;rdquo; in the statistical inference world. The two schools of thought: Deterministic Optimization and Bayesian Statistics have different philosophical frameworks for answering questions pertaining to the explanation of observed data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>