<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resume on Michael Pilosov | Academic Website</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resume on Michael Pilosov | Academic Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Presentations can be sorted/viewed on the Presentations Page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications can be sorted/viewed on the Publications Page.
Manuscripts in review are not shown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/employment/</guid>
      <description> (only showing academic jobs) University of Colorado: Denver (Downtown Campus)  Student Teaching Assistant, Calculus I (Aug-Dec 2016) Student Research Assistant (Jan-Aug 2016) &amp;ldquo;DiaMonD: An Integrated Multifaceted Approach to Mathematics at the Interfaces of Data, Models, and Decisions,&amp;rdquo; DE-SC0009279 Student Teaching Assistant, Calculus I (Aug-Dec 2015) Tutor, Mathematics Education Research Center (Aug-Dec 2015) Student Research Assistant (Aug 2014-May 2015) &amp;ldquo;CAREER: Foundations for Understanding and Reaching the Limits of Standard Numerical Linear Algebra,&amp;rdquo; NSF CCF 1054864 Student Research Assistant (Jun-Aug 2014) &amp;ldquo;SI2-SSI: Collaborative Research: Sustained Innovation for Linear Algebra Software (SILAS),&amp;rdquo; NSF ACI 1339797  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/newyork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/newyork/</guid>
      <description>(only showing academic jobs) State University of New York: College at Geneseo  Teaching Assistant for Linear Programming &amp;amp; Operations Research (Jan-May 2014) Geneseo Research Foundation Undergraduate STEM Summer Research Fellow (Jun-Aug 2013)  Volunteer Data Analyst for As Green As It Gets (Nov-Dec 2012)
Private Tutor in Mathematics (Summer-Fall 2013)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honors &amp; Awards</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/honors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/honors/</guid>
      <description>Research Grants Lynn Bateman Teaching Fellowship 2018, CU Denver
Geneseo Foundation STEM Undergraduate Summer Research Fellowship Grant 2013
Academic Societies Phi Beta Kappa Society 2014, SUNY Geneseo, Alpha Omega Chapter
Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honor Society 2014, SUNY Geneseo, New York Alpha Delta Chapter
Golden Key International Honor Society 2014, SUNY Geneseo
Awards SUNY Geneseo Award for Excellence in Mathematics 2014-2015 (photos)
74th annual William Lowell Putnam Math Competition First Place, Pi Mu Epsilon Alpha Delta Chapter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Skills</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/techskills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/resume/techskills/</guid>
      <description>Python  lead developer of cbayes contributor and researcher on BET extensive experience generating technical notebooks with varying levels of interactivity familiarity with JupyterHub, JupyterLab deep interest in reproducible open science and removing all friction towards such an end  Matlab  first language, used for countless projects. I have since moved away from it in favor of open-source alternatives  Git  familiarity with basic repository management have used Github, Bitbucket, and Gitlab I use it to track changes to nearly all the work I do  LaTeX  preferred document-generation language (pdfs) basic familiarity with publishing formatting for large documents extensive experience writing technical reports  Terminal (Bash/Shell)  Almost everything I do with respect to programming happens in a bash shell Much of my work is done remotely through ssh  Vim  My preferred text-editor and distraction-free organizational tool  Adobe Suite  experienced in Photoshop for general graphic design (posters, figures) familiar with Illustrator  Microsoft Suite  comfortable in Excel, though I prefer not to use it for anything related to analyzing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>