<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>G2S3</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/summerschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/summerschool/</guid>
      <description>Program The summer school was focused on Uncertainty Quantification, specifically pretending to Inverse Problems.
Structure We sat through hours of lecture and about half the days we managed to spend programming/implementing some of what we learned.
Project At the end of the summer school we had to perform a project, and I paired up with a couple of students to work on an inverse problem involving the Helmholtz equation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitterbots</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/twitterbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/twitterbots/</guid>
      <description>I decided to explore the use of Twitter&amp;rsquo;s API in Python to perform some fun projects.
I wrote a Twitter bot called &amp;ldquo;Random Art Baby&amp;rdquo; that when prompted, would respond to users with artwork.
This art was randomly generated using the library I had developed for my initial exploration with graphical user interfaces for visualizing probability distributions.
This also provided me the opportunity to explore some machine learning code for the generation of natural language speech based on training examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</guid>
      <description>After my first experience with writing software in the summer of 2013, I wanted to learn how to write software that was usable by other people1.
I thought that learning how graphical user interfaces work would be a good place to start. Since I already knew Matlab, I chose that for my programming language.
I performed the project under the direction of use of Dr. Yusuf Bilgic, who generally gave me free rein to pursue the project in any direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Websites</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/slides/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/slides/website/</guid>
      <description>Building Websites Core Concepts  Websites are just collections of files Files must exist on computers Servers handle protocols for reading files  This allows files to be remote(ly accessible)  Addresses tell servers where to look for files Domain names are aliases for locations  A DNS acts as a registry of (IP) addresses It associates names to addresses.   Architecture Client: web-browser
 Manages requests for information Makes sense of the responses Some code can be executed on your computer  Javascript allows for all sorts of interactivity It is the &amp;ldquo;programming language&amp;rdquo; of the browser  Security is high priority  Architecture Host: computer where files live</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>