<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>evolution on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in evolution on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Group-level events are catalysts in the evolution of cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/publication/cooperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/publication/cooperation/</guid>
      <description>Some Notes from the (co)author I worked on this topic primarily in summer 2014, with occasional contributions into early 2016 under the direction of Burt Simon. My primary contributions involved handling all software and experimental simulations, but I aided in the narrative framing and editing of the paper as well. There is ample room for extending the work, but ultimately I did not venture into this field for my doctoral research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</guid>
      <description>I began graduate school in the summer of 2014 as a summer graduate research assistant. I approached Dr. Burt Simon to learn about his research as I was casually walking around the department while working on the LAPACK project. His research was concerned with modeling population dynamics to study the conditions under which cooperation could evolve from a mutation to the norm within a system that is inherently competitive.
I was really interested in the problem he was working on and asked if I could see his software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>