<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mentorship on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/mentorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mentorship on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/mentorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Lunch</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mentorlunch/</guid>
      <description>As President of SIAM, I organized a regular mentor lunch that we started to run every semester. What motivated me was noticing that undergraduates with whom I spoke were routinely unaware of their career options. It was completely unclear what courses they should take because they had a hard time connecting what they liked to possible career paths. Many did not know that graduate school could be paid for! The course descriptions were not particularly helpful since they contained jargon that was unfamiliar to students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mathclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary During the last semester of my first year in graduate school (spring 2015), I volunteered for the Study Hall that was being put on by the department. I was inspired by that event to get in touch with the professor who organized it, and asked about interest in a Math Club. I was told that it had languished over the years but I was welcome to revive it (he was willing to be the faculty advisor), and he put me in touch with an undergraduate student that he thought would be good to partner up with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>