<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BET</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/bet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/bet/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/thesis/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G2S3</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/summerschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/summerschool/</guid>
      <description>Program The summer school was focused on Uncertainty Quantification, specifically pretending to Inverse Problems.
Structure We sat through hours of lecture and about half the days we managed to spend programming/implementing some of what we learned.
Project At the end of the summer school we had to perform a project, and I paired up with a couple of students to work on an inverse problem involving the Helmholtz equation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Toxins</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/toxins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/toxins/</guid>
      <description>Overview I went to work with Dr. Velimir Vesselinov in the summer of 2017 at the Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL). This experience drastically changed the direction of my research. I spent much of my time reading papers on Bayesian Inverse Problems and Subsurface Contaminant Transport Problems. Part of what I did was learn the Julia programming language1, implementing some Markov chain Monte Carlo methods to practice, and converting some algorithms from Python to Julia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/masters/</guid>
      <description>Summary My advisor developed a framework for solving a large class of problems of particular interest to the engineering disciplines. Starting as a graduate research assistant under his direction in the summer of 2015, I began to learn about this new method and explore implications of how measurements of physical systems are taken on our ability to accurately describe parameter uncertainty sets.
You can read more about it below, but overall, my focus on skewness ended up playing a less important role when we developed a sample-based approach to solving the same problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistent Bayes</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/cbayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/cbayes/</guid>
      <description>A repository I wrote for my PhD research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DCI</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/dci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/dci/</guid>
      <description>The novel framework for solving inverse problems in which all of my doctoral work has been grounded.
Talk about the method in broad terms. What makes it different?
  Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topics</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/research/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</guid>
      <description>I began graduate school in the summer of 2014 as a summer graduate research assistant. I approached Dr. Burt Simon to learn about his research as I was casually walking around the department while working on the LAPACK project. His research was concerned with modeling population dynamics to study the conditions under which cooperation could evolve from a mutation to the norm within a system that is inherently competitive.
I was really interested in the problem he was working on and asked if I could see his software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAPACK</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/lapack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/lapack/</guid>
      <description>My Brief Experience I was fortunate enough to be funded by Dr. Julien Langou during my summer proceeding entering graduate school. This relief from teaching was especially helpful for my transition into post-graduate education, and I was given the opportunity to explore a number of topics that I knew nothing about.
For the first time, I found myself working on an object-oriented task in a programming language that was strongly typed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>