<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spring 2013 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/spring-2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spring 2013 on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/spring-2013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/chessclub/</guid>
      <description>Summary Along with some good friends, I helped re-establish this defunct club and secure funding for club meetings and events.
My primary responsibilities included all publicity operations and planning the charity fundraisers.
We held weekly meetings and grew from two tables to as many as twelve simultaneous games happening. Snacks were provided and occasionally we were able to provide pizza.
  Waiting for announcements to end so chess can start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Cards</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/blackjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/blackjack/</guid>
      <description>As part of a course I took, I was tasked to perform a semester-long research project on a topic of my choosing. I had a nascent interest in blackjack after seeing the film 21, and wanted to learn more about the history and mathematics behind how/why card counting worked for the MIT blackjack team so well.
This research project was my first introduction of Monte-Carlo methods, probability and expectation, and game theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agricultural Prediction</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/guatemala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/guatemala/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As Green As It Gets (formerly “AGAIG”, now &amp;ldquo;De La Gente&amp;rdquo;/ &amp;ldquo;DLG&amp;rdquo;) is a Non-Governmental Organization founded in 2004 which is focused on the economic development of the coffee farmers that are members of the San Miguel-Escobar coffee cooperative.
By providing loans, planning, and invaluable marketing connections, the organization seeks to direct the profits from coffee sales towards the farmers, allowing them to lift themselves out of poverty and improve opportunities for their children and themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAC</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/mac/</guid>
      <description>Four years of active participation in a Service Organization. Almost countless events.
I joined my first semester in undergrad, and remained an active member every semester that I was enrolled in college.
Pillars of the Organization  Scholarship Service Unity Fitness Loyalty   Here is a reproduction of a Lamron Article about the organization. It was written the semester I joined! 
 Men of Action and Change, an organization founded at Geneseo in 1997, is a multicultural group dedicated to continuing a legacy of service and support to the local and global communities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>