<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on Michael Pilosov: The Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.michaelpilosov.com/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agricultural Prediction &amp; Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/guatemala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/guatemala/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As Green As It Gets (formerly “AGAIG”, now &amp;ldquo;De La Gente&amp;rdquo;/ &amp;ldquo;DLG&amp;rdquo;) is a Non-Governmental Organization founded in 2004 which is focused on the economic development of the coffee farmers that are members of the San Miguel-Escobar coffee cooperative.
By providing loans, planning, and invaluable marketing connections, the organization seeks to direct the profits from coffee sales towards the farmers, allowing them to lift themselves out of poverty and improve opportunities for their children and themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Cards: Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/blackjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/blackjack/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/evolution/</guid>
      <description>I began graduate school in the summer of 2014
You can find more information about the article, including links to code, pdf, and the co-author&amp;rsquo;s website on the publication page.
  Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/probablyart/</guid>
      <description>Please pardon our mess.   This page is still a work in progress.   I have many projects that I am documenting simultaneously and am doing my best to be thorough and embed a lot of rich metadata so that you can click around based on what you find interesting.  Please feel free to contact me if you want me to finish this particular page immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Game of Poker</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/poker/</guid>
      <description>This was a really fun project I undertook for a Math Club game night in 2016 with my friend Elliott Regan, who helped me program this in Javascript and embed into an earlier version of my website.
Premise Dr. Burt Simon and I had previously collaborated on a paper.
Rules The rules are listed in short form below the game demonstration below. Gambling would occur on pre-determined intervals (timer), or whenever someone wants to (if you enjoy a bit of chaos).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Wildlife (on a budget)</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/wildlife/</guid>
      <description>I managed a group of four undergraduates through a semester-long research project concerning the placement of sensors in an environment where the travel patterns of animals is unknown. My responsibilities included:
 defining the scope of research and breaking goals down into explicit deliverables, overseeing timeline of research progress, keeping students on deadline, developing outlines of software and clearly defined what their contributions would be.  We chose to define a problem that everyone had some shared interest in and that would be relevant to Distance Geometry (the topic of the Math Clinic that semester).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharma Mutuals</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelpilosov.com/project/pharma/</guid>
      <description>This was a self-directed research project that had its origins in my desire to better understand the contents of an enticing TED talk that I watched during the first week of my last semester as an undergraduate student.
  What grabbed my attention was that the speaker (Stein) invited scrutiny of their source code, making it [publicly available on GitHub][code]. This event likely seeded my interest in open-source philosophies and diving into this project was an early attempt to learn more about how other people write code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>