<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academia on Mathematical Michael</title>
    <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/categories/academia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academia on Mathematical Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/categories/academia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assets for SIAM Advertising</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/resources/siam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/resources/siam/</guid>
      <description>I have been advertising events hosted by SIAM for several years now as part of my dedication to service to my graduate department at CU Denver. One thing I consistently struggled with was finding high-quality versions of the SIAM logo for use in the posters I was making.
I still do not understand why their website assets are consistently ranked as irrelevant on Google image search For the longest time I was pulling images from other people&amp;rsquo;s websites that Google was scraping more successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Toxins</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/project/contaminant-transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/project/contaminant-transport/</guid>
      <description>More to Come Soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Good Advising: Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising3/</guid>
      <description>You have to find someone you want to learn from.
That is what can make the difference between five years in graduate school and seven years. It can mean the difference between being lost and being directed in a productive manner.
Maybe I got lucky, but my present advisor has rarely let me go in a research direction that didn&amp;rsquo;t bear fruit of some kind or another. He knew when to shield me from complexity and when to implore me to pursue deeper understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Good Advising: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising2/</guid>
      <description>Getting to Grad School As an undergraduate, I first experienced the extent to which mathematics could be broadly applied to &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; problems, and recognized the potential to make substantive change. I set my sights on a job in industry, with vague hopes and aspirations as to what such a thing might look like. I had been applying to summer programs that would potentially expose me to application areas every.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Good Advising: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mathematicalmichael.com/post/advising1/</guid>
      <description>Opportunistic Disparity and Serendipity This past summer I worked at a national laboratory that sees several thousand students come through its doors each year to develop their skills and networks. Orientation blew my mind. When my group was surveyed regarding where we were academically, I realized that graduate students made up something like a tenth of the room.
 Wait&amp;hellip; how did these kids get jobs here so early on?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>